你们知道这是最后一次 我们以六个单身朋友的身份…
Do you realize this is the last time we'll be here in the coffeehouse...
共聚一堂吗？
...as six single people?
咖啡厅怎么了？
What's happening to the coffeehouse?
好
Oh! Okay.
从现在开始 是你们四个好朋友 我跟我太太了
From now on, it's you four and me and the missus.
我的小女人 好老婆 老的系绊
The little woman. The wife. The old ball and chain.
- 老的？ - 你是年轻性感的系绊
- Old?     - The young, hot ball and chain.
- 好多了   - 我们得走了
- Much better.     - We gotta go.
- 去哪里？ - 我要去拿婚纱 跟妈一起吃午餐
- Where?     - Get the dress and lunch with mom.
乔伊 你也要去？
Joey, you too?
我只是听到"午餐"
I just heard "lunch."
对 我可以去 当然
Yeah, I can go. Sure.
事实上我很高兴他们离开了
Actually, I'm glad they're leaving.
有件事我得跟你谈一谈
I need to talk to you about something.
- 什么事？ - 这或许会有点尴尬
- What's up?      - This may be a little awkward.
如果你需要钱 时机真的不太对 明天晚上我得请一百二十八个人吃晚餐
If you need money, it's a bad time. I'm buying dinner for 128 people tomorrow.
不 不是那样的
No, it's not that.
我不是以你朋友的身份跟你说话…
I'm not gonna say this as your friend...
我要以摩妮卡大哥的身份跟你谈
...but as Monica's older brother.
- 但你还是我朋友吧？ - 接下来的几分钟不是
- But you're still my friend?     - Not for a few minutes.
- 现在你还是我的伴郎吗？ - 不是
- Right now, are you still my best man?     - No.
- 我还是可以叫你罗斯吗？ - 好
- Do I still call you Ross?      - Okay.
你们要结婚了 我真的很高兴
You guys are getting married, and I couldn't be more thrilled.
但身为她的大哥 我得告诉你一件事
But as Monica's older brother, I have to tell you this:
如果你敢伤害我妹妹…
If you ever hurt my little sister...
如果你敢让她不快乐…
...if you ever cause her any unhappiness of any kind...
天涯海角我都会找到你…
...I will hunt you down...
然后痛扁你
...and kick your ass.
干嘛？我是认真的
What? I'm serious.
- 兄弟 别闹了 我不是在开玩笑   - 我听到你的话了…
- Dude! Stop it! I'm not kidding.     - I hear what you're saying...
谢谢你的警告
...and thanks for the warning.
别客气
No problem.
我们又是朋友了？
So are we friends again?
- 对   - 好
- Yeah.     - Okay.
你不会相信刚刚摩妮卡的 哥哥跟我说了什么
Ahem. You won't believe what Monica's brother just said to me!
你在做什么 摩妮卡？
What you doing, Mon?
我在列出 婚礼上可能会出差错的事情
I'm listing all the things that could go wrong at the wedding.
那样子我可以做好准备
So I can be prepared.
- 哪些事会出差错？ - 目前为止有伴娘的礼服忘了拿…
- Mm-hm. What are they?     - "The dresses won't get picked up...
我的头纱不见 或是我忘了拿蓝色的东西
...veil gets lost, and I'm missing something blue."
那些都是我负责的事
Those are all the things I'm responsible for.
我总得看机率啊
I had to go with the odds.
喂 各位
Hey! You guys!
你们还记得之前我去试镜 没有拿到那个角色的事吗？
Remember I had that audition a while ago, and I didn't get that part?
- 那个广告？ - 不是
- The commercial?     - No.
- 那出舞台剧？ - 不是
- That play?     - No.
- 另一出舞台剧？ - 不是
- That other play?     - No.
- 那部电影？ - 对
- The movie?     - Yes!
- 那部狗会开飞机的电影？ - 不是
- The one about the pilot and his dog?     - No.
但我真的很伤心
But man, that one hurt.
- 这部电影在描述一次大战的士兵   - 喔 对喔
- This is the one about WWI soldiers.     - Oh, yeah.
以前我们叫它"大战"
Back then we called it "The Great War."
它真的是大战
It really was.
他们录取的那个角色不演了  我今天就要开始拍戏
A guy they wanted backed out and now they want me! I start shooting today!
恭喜
Congratulations!
- 今天有彩排晚宴   - 我一定会赶过去的
- Today's the rehearsal dinner.     - I'll be done by then.
喔 那么太棒了 你成了电影明星
Oh. Then way to go, you big movie star!
待会见 我要去跟纳粹作战了
See you. I'm off to fight the Nazis.
纳粹是我们在二次大战的敌人 不是一次大战
Wait, Joey. We fought the Nazis in WWll, not WWI.
好
Whoa. Okay.
谁是我们在一次大战的敌人？
Who was in WWI?
你说吧
Go ahead.
- 你要迟到了 快去…   - 好 晚点再见
- You're gonna be late! Go! Go!     - Yeah, I'll see you.
谁是我们在一次大战的敌人？
Who did we fight in WWI?
- 墨西哥？ - 对 非常棒
- Mexico?     - Yes. Very good.
(五十九号码头片厂)
- 嘿 乔伊 我们准备好了   - 我也是
- Hey, Joey. We're ready.     - Yeah, me too.
理查 我们准备好了
Richard, we're ready for you.
乔伊崔比亚尼 这位是理查克洛斯比 他要饰演文森
Joey Tribbiani, Richard Crosby is playing Vincent.
- 我要跟你演对手戏？ - 很高兴能认识你
- I'm doing my scenes with you?     - Nice to meet you.
我不敢相信 这太不可思议了 你刚刚拿下奥斯卡金像奖
I can't believe this. Incredible. You just won an Oscar.
不 我没有
No, I didn't.
我知道你有
I think you did.
我想我输了三次
I think I lost, three times.
- 饼干？你要…？ - 不
- Uh, cookie? Would you?     - No.
再过一小时我们就要正式开拍
Okay. We're about an hour away from getting the scene lit.
- 你们能对一下戏吗？ - 没问题
- So, uh, can you guys run it a couple times?     - Yeah, sure.
好了 我们开始吧
All right. Let's do it.
好了…开始
And action!
- 我们得找到其他士兵    - 算了吧 他们已经不在了
- We have to find the platoon!     - Forget the platoon. The platoon is gone!
- 什么？ - 他们都死了 面对现实吧 东尼
- What?     - The platoon's dead! Face facts, Tony!
我们该怎么办？ 我们没有援兵或食物
What'll we do? We have no reinforcements or food.
地下室有食物 有马铃薯跟一些意大利面
There's food in the basement. Potatoes and some pasta.
等一下 乔伊 你一直在摸你的脸
Hang on. Joey, you keep touching your face.
有什么问题吗？
Something wrong?
不 没有
No.
我…
I, uh...
我以为这么做会很酷
I thought it might be a cool character thing.
他是个喜欢摸脸的人
He's a face toucher.
我可不那么认为
I don't think so.
我们从理查 最后一句台词开始 开始
Let's take it back to Richard's last lines. Action!
虽然我们没有武器 但我们还有食物 地下室有…
We may not have any weapons, but we still have food.
马铃薯 意大利面…
Potatoes, pasta...
跟几罐鲔鱼
...and a few tins of tuna!
- 甜心 我们得走了    - 好
- Honey, we gotta go!     - Okay.
这个问题真的很难启齿
Here's a question you never want to ask:
我爸刚打来 问能不能借用你的珍珠项链
My dad just called and wants to know if he can borrow one of your pearl necklaces?
他有提到 他的领口剪裁是哪一种吗？
Did he say what kind of neckline he's wearing?
没有
No.
我只见过他一次 但我猜 是低胸的？
I've only met him once but I'm guessing, plunging?
他是那种不吓死人不罢休的爸爸
He is more of a "If you've got it, flaunt it" kind of father.
我没有那种项链 我去问问瑞秋有没有
I don't have anything but let me see if Rachel does.
对 把更多的人扯进来
Yes, include more people in this.
你知道明天这个时候 我们要结婚吗？
Hey. Do you realize that tomorrow we're gonna be getting married?
我明天晚上有约了
I have a date tomorrow night.
- 我不敢相信我们真的办到了   - 别一副很讶异的样子
- I can't believe we made it.     - You don't have to sound so surprised.
对不起 但是…
I'm sorry, but...
- 没事   - 什么？
- Nothing.     - What?
老实说 自从我们订婚后…
Well, honestly? Ever since we got engaged...
我一直在期待 发生什么事让你退缩
...I've waited for you to flip out.
真的吗？我也是
Honestly? Me too.
- 真的吗？ - 对
- Really?     - Yeah.
我以为会发生什么蠢事 然后我会做…
I think that something stupid will come up and I'll...
钱德会做的事
...go all Chandler.
- 但什么事都没发生   - 我很高兴
- But nothing has.     - I'm so glad.
谢谢你在这段时间 一直都非常冷静
Thank you for staying so calm during this.
这让我非常地冷静
It's made me stay calm.
- 我可能会更差的   - 好
- I could've been worse.     - Okay.
我马上回来
I'll be right there.
如果你在星期六前打电话来…
Hi, if you're calling before Saturday...
这里是摩妮卡跟钱德家
...you've reached Monica and Chandler.
但如果你在星期六后打电话来 这里就是宾氏夫妇家
But if you're calling after Saturday, you've reached Mr. And Mrs. Bing.
请留话给宾氏夫妇
Please leave a message for the Bings!
- 嘿 玛琳    - 嗨
- Maureen!     - Hi.
- 天啊 她是我表妹玛琳   - 我们是宾氏夫妇
- Gosh. This is my cousin, Maureen.     - We're the Bings.
嗨 你们都很好看
Hi! You guys look so beautiful.
宾先生跟宾太太
Mr. And Mrs. Bing!
哇 摩妮卡
Wow, Monica.
让你知道一下 我以 "大哥的身分"跟钱德谈过
So you know, I had my older-brother talk with Chandler.
- 你说了什么？ - 嗯…
- What is that?     - Well, I...
我告诉他如果他敢伤害你…
I told him that if he ever hurt you...
天涯海角我都会找到他 然后痛扁他
...I would hunt him down and kick his ass.
大家是怎么了？我是认真的
What is the matter with everybody? I'm serious.
我会痛扁他
I would kick his ass!
罗斯 拜托 我的妆要糊掉了
Ross, please, my makeup!
嗨
Hi.
- 钱德   - 妈
- Chandler.     - Mom.
谢谢你记得穿… 衣服来
Thanks for wearing... something.
我真的很兴奋 我以为我们害得你不敢结婚
Ohh. This is so exciting! I thought we screwed you up too much for this.
你想想 很快地 就会出现很多宾氏小孩
Just think, soon there will be lots of little Bings.
我不敢相信我要回去 让人家喷口水
I can't believe I have to go back to work after this and get spit on again.
你很幸运 至少喷你口水的人都很有名
You're lucky. At least the people who spit on you are famous.
- 谁对你喷口水？ - 我不想谈工作的事
- Who spits on you?     - I don't wanna talk about work.
宾太太？他们是我爸妈 茱蒂跟杰克盖勒
Mrs. Bing? These are my parents, Judy and Jack Geller.
- 很高兴能见到你   - 你是他妈妈还是他爸爸？
- It's lovely to meet you.     - Are you his mother or father?
杰克
Jack!
干嘛？我没看过变性人啊
What? I've never seen one before.
爸 罗斯在那边 去跟他谈一谈吧
Dad, there's Ross. Go talk to him.
我甚至没办法 假装我不会在意
I didn't even have a chance to act as if I'm okay with it.
大家好
Hello, all.
嗨… 爸
Hi... Dad.
嗨 宾先生
Hi, Mr. Bing.
- 诺拉   - 查尔斯
- Nora.     - Charles.
- 很高兴你们两个都来了   - 对
- It's so great to see you both here.     - Yes.
虽然有些人是衣不蔽体
Although we may be seeing too much of some people.
你不觉得自己太老了 不该穿那种衣服吗？
Aren't you too old to wear a dress like that?
你不觉得自己是个男人 不该穿那种衣服吗？
Don't you have too much penis to wear a dress like that?
喔 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你当然可以痛扁他 儿子
Of course you can kick his ass, son.
你想痛扁任何人都没有问题
You could kick anyone's ass you want to.
谢谢你们
Thanks, you guys.
- 瑞秋？ - 干嘛？
- Rach, Rach?     - Yeah?
帮个忙 去跟钱德的老爸聊天 别让他跟钱德的老妈杠上了
Do me a favor. Talk to Chandler's dad and keep him away from Chandler's mom.
- 好 但我不知道他长什么样子   - 他穿着黑色洋装
- Yeah, but I don't know what he looks like.     - He is the man in a black dress.
嗨 我是瑞秋 摩妮卡跟钱德的朋友
Hi. I'm Rachel, a friend of Monica and Chandler's.
- 我是亚曼达   - 喔 我懂了
- I'm Amanda.      - Oh, I get it.
男人 啊
"A man, duh!"
请大家听我说
Could I have your attention?
- 我是罗斯盖勒   - 罗斯盖勒博士
- I'm Ross Geller.     - Dr. Ross Geller.
爸 拜托 我刚刚说过…
Dad, please. As I was saying...
我是罗斯盖勒博士
...I'm Dr. Ross Geller.
我是伴郎
Uh, and I'm the best man.
这段婚姻对我来说有双重意义…
And this marriage is doubly special for me...
不只因为新郎是我的好朋友…
...um, because not only is the groom my best friend...
更因为新娘是我的妹妹
...but, uh, the bride is my little sister.
她是所有男人梦寐以求的好妹妹
She's the greatest sister a guy could ask for.
请大家跟我一起举杯…
Please join me in raising a glass...
敬这对新人
...to the couple we're here to celebrate.
- 敬宾氏夫妇   - 敬宾氏夫妇
- To the Bings.     - To the Bings!
我要去熨婚纱了
I'm gonna steam my dress.
谁负责确定它不会有问题？
Who will make sure nothing happens to it?
- 我会负责   - 谁要负责？有人愿意吗？
- I'll do it.     - Who wants it? Anybody?
- 我说我会负责   - 没有人吗？
- I said I'll do it.     - Nobody?
- 好吧 那我就自己来   - 我不会搞砸的
- All right, I'll do it myself.     - I'm not gonna screw it up.
你说得对 对不起 今晚你帮了大忙
You're right. I'm sorry. You were a big help tonight.
谢谢你帮忙 将我奶奶安全地送回饭店
And thanks for putting my grandmother in the cab to get to the hotel.
- 当然 那就是我的工作   - 好吧 对不起
- Of course! That's what I'm here for.     - Okay. Sorry.
额
Ugh! Pssh.
什么奶奶？
What grandmother?
- 你跑到哪里去了？ - 我送我爸妈回饭店
- Where have you been?     - Taking my parents to the hotel.
- 你要回去工作了？ - 对
- Going back to work?     - Yeah.
- 很酷的太阳眼镜   - 我想如果我能戴上它拍戏…
- Nice shades.     - If I wear these in my scenes...
我的眼睛就不会喷到口水了
...I won't get spit in my eyes.
如果我没有记错 雷朋是一次大战的正式赞助商
And, if I remember correctly, Ray-Ban was the official sponsor of WWI.
太棒了 帅啊
Great! All right!
- 晚点见   - 好吧
- I'll see you later.     - All right.
- 钱德在哪里？ - 我想他在瑞秋的房间里 再见
- Where's Chandler?      - I think he's in Rachel's room. See you.
钱德？
Chandler?
- 嘿    - 嗨
- Hey.      - Hi.
- 摩妮卡在吗？ - 她在熨婚纱 怎么了？
- Is Monica here?      - She's steaming her dress. Why?
- 我想钱德走了   - 什么？
- I think Chandler's gone.     - What?
- 他留下了这个   - "告诉摩妮卡我很抱歉"
- He left that.      - "Tell Monica I'm sorry."
喔 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
怎么了？
What's up?
"告诉摩妮卡我很抱歉"
"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
你自己去告诉她
Tell her yourself.
喔 我的天啊 钱德走了？
Oh, my God. Chandler just left, though?
或许事情不是我们想的那样 或许他是说
Maybe it's not what we think. Maybe it's:
"告诉摩妮卡我很抱歉 我把牛奶都喝光了"
"Tell Monica I'm sorry I drank the last of the milk."
或许他写这张字条告诉她 他改了名字
Or maybe he was writing to tell her that he's changed his name:
"告诉摩妮卡我叫抱歉"
"Tell Monica, I'm Sorry."
- 这表示他吓得逃跑了   - 别那么消极
- It means he freaked out and left!      - Don't be so negative!
天啊 有没有可能"抱歉" 现在就坐在里面
Good God, isn't it possible that "Sorry" is sitting in there right now?
菲比 我想罗斯说得对 我们该怎么办？
Phoebe, I think Ross is right. What are we gonna do?
我得去找他 把他带回来
I'm gonna have to go find him and bring him back.
你们别让摩妮卡 发现这件事 好吗？
You make sure Monica does not find out, okay?
好 但是你如果没办法找到他 把他带回来…
But, if you don't find him and bring him back...
天涯海角我都会找到你 然后痛扁你
...I am gonna hunt you down and kick your ass!
我会找到他的
I will find him.
乔伊 你能跟我对一下台词吗？
Joey? Can you go through these lines with me?
喔 天啊 他们才帮我补好妆
Oh, man, they just re-did my makeup.
- 只要对最后两页   - 好吧
- Just the last two pages.      - All right.
我发现照片了
I found the picture!
照片？什么照片？
Picture? What picture?
我在你的背包里 发现我太太的照片
The picture of my wife! I found it in your pack!
你能把剧本放下来吗？
Could you lower the script?
我不想
I don't want to.
我得看到你的脸 才能依你的反应演出
I need to see your face so I can play off your reaction.
好吧 听我说
Okay, look.
我知道你的演技很棒 演过很多莎翁名剧…
I know you're great and play all those Shakespeare guys...
但你喷得我满脸是口水
...but you're spitting all over me, man.
- 那当然    - 你知道你会喷口水？
- Of course I am!      - You know you've been spitting?
真正的演员都会那么做
That's what real actors do.
清晰地发音是好演员的注册商标
Enunciation is the mark of a good actor.
清晰地发音时就会喷口水
And when you enunciate, you spit!
我不知道这件事
Wow. Didn't know that.
谢了 好吧 看我的
Thanks. Okay, check it out.
照片？什么照片？
Picture? What picture?
- 阿甘 你看到钱德了吗？ - 不 我没有看到他
- Have you seen Chandler?     - No, I haven't seen him.
- 该死   - 他明天要结婚了 对吧？
- Damn.      - He's getting married tomorrow, right?
对 别担心 一切都会没事的
Yes. Don't worry. Everything's fine.
- 明天婚礼上见   - 我没有被邀请
- See you at the wedding.      - I wasn't invited.
那么后天见
Then we'll see you the day after tomorrow.
妈？爸？
Mom? Dad?
你们在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
你们老是聊到这个地方 我们想看看这里有什么特别的
You kids talk about this place so much, we thought we'd see what the fuss is all about.
- 我知道为什么女孩们喜欢来这里   - 为什么？
- I see why the girls like coming here.      - Why?
为了吧台后面那个性感大帅哥
The sexy blond behind the counter.
- 阿甘？ - 她刚刚把他列入她的名单
- Gunther?      - She just added him to her list.
- 什么？你的名单？ - 我们可以上床的对象…
- Your list?     - Of people we're allowed to sleep...
我知道那是什么样的名单
I know what the list is.
快坐下吧 喝杯咖啡
Sit down, have a cup of joe.
爸 我没空 抱歉
I can't, I'm sorry.
如果你们看到钱德 告诉他我在找他
If you see Chandler, tell him I'm looking for him.
如果你看到丽塔莫雷诺 告诉她我在找她
And if you see Rita Moreno, let her know I'm looking for her.
开始
Action!
我发现照片了
I found the picture!
什么照片？
What picture?
我在你的背包里 发现我太太的照片
A picture of my wife, in your pack!
你偷翻我的私人物品？
You went through my personal property?
你的背包里 为什么会有宝丽蒂的照片？
Why do you have a picture of Paulette in your pack?
文森 因为我们…
Because, Vincent, we were lovers...
交往过两年
...for two years!
卡 太棒了
Cut! Wonderful!
真的是太棒了
Great scene, huh?
你真的很棒 最后那一段你喷得我的脸都湿了
You were awesome. In that last speech, you soaked me.
- 这是明天的通告表   - 明天我不会工作
- Tomorrow's call sheet.     - I'm not working tomorrow.
- 现在是了   - 不 你得帮我这个忙
- You are now.      - No, you gotta get me out of it.
我已经有约了 这件事非常重要
I have plans. Important plans!
- 罗斯说还是没有钱德的消息   - 喔 天啊
- Still no word from Chandler.      - Oh, man.
但他们发现 奶奶在第五大道上游荡
But they found the grandmother wandering down 5th.
好吧 至少找到一个人了
Okay, well there's one down.
我今天要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
我断了一根肋骨 但我不在乎 我今天要结婚了
I cracked a rib, but I don't care. Today's my wedding!
我终于要结婚了
My day is finally here!
或许她不会注意到他不见了
She might not even notice he's gone.
我要开始准备了
I'm gonna start getting ready!
我们不能让她开始准备 这太可怕了
We can't let her start getting ready. This is too awful!
等她换上婚纱 而他又没有出现时…
She'll be in the gown, and he won't show up.
这时候她得脱掉婚纱…
Then she'll have to take off the gown...
冷静点 你不能在这里抓狂
Stop it. You can't do this here.
对不起 抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
那真的是太悲伤了
It's just so sad.
振作一点 别让她看到你这个样子
Pull it together. She can't see you like this.
- 她会发现不对劲的   - 我知道 天啊
- She'll know something's wrong.     - I know. I know.
没有面纸了
There's no tissue.
你能拿张卫生纸给我吗？
Can you grab me some toilet paper?
喔 卫生纸也没有了 这里是摩妮卡的浴室吧？
Oh, that's gone too. This is Monica's bathroom, right?
- 我找到一张了   - 好吧
- I found one.      - Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
喔 天啊
Oh, God.
能再给我一张吗？
Can I have another one?
没问题
Sure.
你需要牙线吗？
Do you need some floss?
我无法想像如果他不出现 会发生什么事
I can't imagine what will happen if he doesn't show up.
这里有一大堆卫生纸
Here's a whole bunch.
她会在礼堂等他…
She'll be at the wedding waiting...
大家会窃窃私语 "喔 那个可怜的女孩"
...and people will be whispering, "That poor girl."
然后她得回来这里 独自一个人过生活
Then she'll have to come back here and live alone.
- 喔 我的天啊   - 干嘛？
- Oh, my God.      - What?
垃圾桶有一根验孕棒 是阳性反应
There was a pregnancy test in the garbage, and it's positive.
摩妮卡怀孕了
Monica's pregnant.
我猜她不会寂寞了
So I guess she won't be totally alone.
下集提要
Next time on Friends:
- 我们得告诉她他失踪了   - 不 我们不能那么做
- We've gotta tell her that he's gone.      - No, we can't.
她很快就会开始做准备
She's gonna start getting ready soon.
你不能拖延她吗？
Can't you stall her a little?
我永远都没办法结婚了
I'm never gonna get married.
我们只拍一场戏 就你跟理查 他是职业高手
We've just got one short scene. It's just you and Richard, and he's a pro.
- 你喝醉了吗？ - 没有
- Are you drunk?     - No!
- 你喝醉了    - 好吧
- Yes, you are!     - All right.
- 钱德还好吗？ - 他好极了
- How's Chandler?      - Great!
- 你在哪里？ - 我还在片场里
- Where are you?     - On the set.
这将会是有史以来 最糟糕的一场婚礼
This is turning into the worst wedding day ever.